davidlebovitz.com 2019-07-07

# Privacy Policy - David Lebovitz

This privacy policy sets out our privacy policies and practices regarding the personal data that we collect from our users at https://www.davidlebovitz.com the (“Website”) and related services. Your use of and/or registration on any aspect of the Website will constitute your agreement to this privacy policy. If you cannot agree with the terms and conditions of this privacy policy, please do not use the Website.

The owner of this Website respects the privacy of readers and provides the Website for entertainment purposes only and for the personal, non-commercial use of its readers. Readers are welcome to subscribe to the Website via Feedburner as well as receive newsletter updates. Feedburner as well as other related services that allow access to the Website are subject to privacy and data collection privacy policies that may differ from this privacy policy. You are responsible for reading, understanding and accepting such policies. Both use an **opt-in** sign-up process so in order to receive either of those you will need to enter a valid e-mail address, then confirm it via a subsequent e-mail message. To be removed from the Mad Mimi (RSS) and newsletter delivery services, follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each e-mail message or other instructions that Mad Mimi or related services provides.

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this Website, it will be used in accordance with this privacy statement. When you use this Website, the following information may be collected:

-Name and e-mail address  
-Website URL  
-Demographic information (such as IP addresses) or other information that does not permit the identification of individual persons.

Demographic, technical, and other information is gathered to enhance the reader experience and ensure that continued operation of the Website. In addition, information that users voluntarily provide through the Website, such as comments or board posts will be collected and maintained on the Website. E-mails sent to the operator of the Website will also be collected and stored.

In general, all personal information submitted to us is used to either respond to a request you make or to aid us in serving you better. Your personal data will not knowingly be sold to a third party, except in the event of a sale, transfer, merger or acquisition (in whole or part) of the Website, in which case you hereby give the consent to your personal data transferred to the subsequent owner or controller of the Website. In addition, although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “Affiliates”), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your Personal Data with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

Use of the contact form, note that the owner may keep contact form submissions for a certain period, but information submitted through the form won’t be used for marketing purposes.

This Privacy Policy does not cover information collected elsewhere, including without limitation offline and on sites linked to from the Website. Once you have used these links to leave the Website, we do not have any control over that other Website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting other sites and you should exercise appropriate caution when visiting linked Websites.

We are committed to protecting the privacy of your data. We use a variety of methods to help protect your personal information. Despite these measures, you should know that the risk associated with submitting your personal data will never be eliminated, and your personal data could be accessed through an unauthorized user or through an inadvertent disclosure.

As of May 2018, this site has been working to be in compliance with all applicable rules regarding [GPDR](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation). The ad network that provides ads on the site, [BlogHer/Momentum](https://www.blogher.com/momentum/75479), has provided information and guidelines for compliance. If you find something that should be addressed, please [contact them](http://www.blogher.com/publishing-network/contact-us) or [the owner](https://www.davidlebovitz.com/contact/) of this site.

You may request deletion of your personal data by us, but we may be required by law or otherwise to keep this information. In addition, while we may delete your personal information from our active servers, your personal information may remain in our archives or data backup systems maintained by us or our service providers.

Notice to California Residents – Your California Privacy Rights (As Provided by California Civil Code section 1798.83):

A California resident who has provided Personal Data to a business with whom he/she has established a business relationship for personal, family, or household purposes (a “California Customer”) may request information about whether the business has disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. In general, if the business has made such a disclosure of Personal Data, upon receipt of a request by a California Customer, the business is required to provide a list of all third parties to whom Personal Data was disclosed in the preceding calendar year, as well as a list of the categories of Personal Data that were disclosed. California Customers may request further information about our compliance with this law by e-mailing [Contact Email for Privacy Questions]. Please note that we are required to respond to one request per California Customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address.

For users residing outside of the United States of America, your Personal Data may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of Personal Data may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Cookies

Most browsers contain “cookies”, which allows the Website to store certain data about your visit. When a reader leaves a comment, along with other identifying information, that information is stored so that on subsequent visits readers do not have to re-enter that information again. Sensitive information, like name, phone numbers, and addresses are not collected or stored unless users leave them on the Website itself. The owner of the Website does not advise readers to post sensitive information where it can be read by others.

Users of the Website have the ability to block or remove cookies by using the methods prescribed by their browsers (such as Firefox, Safari, and Chrome). Visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using this Website, with the drawback that certain features of this Website may not function properly without the aid of cookies. You may also use a similar feature to delete any current cookies. Please refer to your browser’s Help area for assistance with enabling and disabling cookies.

“Click tracking” is also used, which gathers information where readers click on the Website. The Website owner does not track individual’s click patterns and the information is collected for the sole purpose of troubleshooting and/or gathering information about the user base as a whole.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

## Ads

Ads appearing on the Website may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by this Website and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers here or at their site(s). Please visit the privacy policies of those sites for further information.

Google appears on this Website as a third party vendor, and uses cookies to serve ads on this Website. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on your visit to this Website. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google Privacy Center](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/), which allows users to opt-out and manage ad preferences. For information about opting out of Gourmet Ads and ad serving partners please visit [here](http://www.gourmetads.com/about/privacy-policy), Sovern [here](http://at%20http//www.lijit.com/company/privacy-policy), and BlogHer [here](http://www.sheknows.com/privacy-policy).

## Personal Information

Our servers, statistics-gathering software, and WordPress may also automatically collect information about your computer when you visit the Website, including without limitation the type of browser software you use, the operating system you are running, the Website that referred you, and your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. Your IP address is usually associated with the place from which you enter the Internet, like your Internet Service Provider, your company or your university.

For more information about the servers and/or WordPress, please read their privacy policies:

–[WordPress Privacy Policy](http://wordpress.org/about/privacy/) (Blogging Platform)

–[Liquid Web Privacy Policy](https://www.liquidweb.com/about/policies/privacy.html) (Server)

–[Amazon Web Services](http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496) (Secondary Server)

Limited access to our database is also given to third parties that provide us with services, such as technical maintenance and assistance, but only for the purpose of and to the extent necessary to provide those services. These people are website designers and technicians. You expressly consent to the sharing of your personal information with our contractors or other service providers for the sole purpose of providing the services of the Website.

## Comments

When you leave a comment, your IP (internet protocol) address is recorded. For more information about IP addresses visit [IP Address](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address) (Wikipedia). This information can be used to block or ban users from the Website. When you leave a comment on the Website, you do so with the knowledge that it can be edited or deleted at the discretion of the owner of the Website. Malicious or comments with false information are removed as soon as possible. Please use appropriate caution when divulging personal information in the comments as that information is visible and available to the public at large.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. For users that register on this website (if any), we also store the personal information users provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

This information is provided by WordPress, the blogging platform that this site uses:

“If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.”

For further guidelines, please read the [Comment Policy](https://www.davidlebovitz.com/comment-policy/).

This Website is intended for use of people over the age of 13 years old.

* * *

This Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time: the most recent revisions will appear on this page, so check back here frequently to be apprised of any changes. Any such update or modification will be effective immediately. It is your responsibility to review this privacy policy from time to time to ensure that you continue to agree with all of its terms. Continued access and use of this Website by you will constitute your acceptance of any changes or revisions to the Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with these policies, please discontinue use of this Website.
